# Vivek Kumar

Software Engineer

# STRENGTHS

Self-motivated, quick learner and positive thinking.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- 1. Received a best project award in academics.
- 2. Passed LinkdIn Skill Assessment (CSS).

## CONTACT



Mathura



+91-9997719602



vivek.iitd93@gmail.com

# **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2020

MCA (COMPUTER SCI. & ENGG.)

Institute of Management and **Entrepreneurship Development**, Pune

Score 8.5 CGPA

# **PRO.SKILLS**

Good communication

**Problem solving** 

Attention to detail

**Flexibility** 

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A talented individual with overall 2+ years of IT experience in software development encompassing a wide range of skills in developing and supporting applications. Looking to pursue a challenging career and be a part of a progressive organization.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Nov 2021 - Present

Working as a Software Engi.. at Novigo Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

#### Nov 2020 - Nov 2021

Worked as a Front End Developer at Tentackles Strategic Design Pvt. Ltd.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ES6, Node.Js, RESTful API, Express.Js, Material UI.
- Database Technologies: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Other Technologies: Cubels, Git, Github
- Tools: Postman, Microsoft Office, VS Code, Swagger.
- Operating System: Windows 7/8.1/10

# **PROJECTS**

#### 1. STC Dashboard

Process Name: STC Dashboard is an analytical dashboard project to manage all the KPIs using charts

## 2. Timesheet Management System (TMS)

Process Name: TMS Application is a microservice application project to manage the organization's resources timely for business intelligence.

# 3. Tentackles Website

Process Name: They help brands connect with the world through digital experiences that engage, entertain and inspire. They create animations to make our designs interactive and appealing. The process of designing any great product-app, website, or other- mainly incorporates the best use of colours and design in a proper way.

#### RESPONIBILITIES

- Designed, Developed and Maintained applications and websites.
- Writing Webservices and Integration of third party API's and services.
- Testing, Deploying and Monitoring the solutions on cloud.
- Code Reviews through the development of application life cycle.
- Documenting features and technical specifications.

## CERTIFICATION COURSES AND TRAININGS

- MERN Stack Development from Udemy.
- Full Stack Development under the BridgeLabz Solution Pvt
- Short-term Udemy course for knowledge and skills enhancement.